Jiahuan Pei

□ ppsunrise99@gmail.com

https://jiahuan-pei.github.io/





I am a researcher at Dutch national research institute <u>CWI</u>, working on generative dialogue systems in extended reality (XR) spaces. Formerly, I was an applied scientist at Amazon's A9 team, working on core NLP/IR in Amazon product search. I have pursued my Ph.D. with the <u>IRLab</u> at University of Amsterdam, supervised by Prof. dr. Maarten de Rijke and Prof. dr. Pengjie Ren. My interest includes natural language processing (dialogue systems, word embedding, parsing, summarization) and information retrieval (query understanding, recommender system, matching algorithm embedding).

Education

Oct. 2017 – Dec. 2022 Ph.D., University of Amsterdam, Science of Informatics.

Thesis title: Collaborative agents for task-oriented dialogue systems. [link]

Supervisor: Prof. dr. Maarten de Rijke

Sept. 2014 – Jul. 2017 M.Sc., Dalian University of Technology, Computer Applied Technology.

Thesis title: Research on Chinese word semantic similarity computation. [link]

Supervisor: Prof. dr. Degen Huang

Sept. 2010 – Jul. 2014 **B.Sc., Dalian Maritime University,** Software Engineering (Major), International Economics and Trade (Minor).

Thesis title: Chinese functional maximal-length noun phrase recognition. [link]

Supervisor: Assoc. Prof. Yiwu Xie

Skills & Certificate

Knowledge Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Information Retrieval.

Coding Python, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Theano, Java, C, C++, C#, Ruby, PHP, HTML, JavaScript,

SQL, LTEX, AWS (Athena, Sagemaker, S3, Stepfunctions).

Languages Mandarin Chinese (First language), English (IELTS-6.5/CET-6), Japanese (JLPT-N2).

Teaching TLC-module Training (Teaching and Learning Centre, University of Amsterdam).

Experience

April. 2023 - Now

Researcher, CWI, Amsterdam, Netherlands.

My role is to explore generative dialogue agents in extended reality (XR), which cooperates with multiple partners in the EU-supported project. This work combines the fields of artificial intelligence, natural language processing, and immersive technologies to create interactive and engaging conversational experiences in virtual and augmented reality environments. Within the realm of XR, we explore innovative ways to enhance human-computer interactions by enabling natural and realistic conversations with virtual entities. By leveraging the power of generative dialogue systems, you aim to develop intelligent agents capable of understanding and responding to user input in a dynamic and contextually appropriate manner.

Experience (continued)

Dec. 2021 - Mar. 2023

Applied Scientist, Amazon, Berlin, Germany.

My role is to explore practical NLP/IR problems related to customer obsession with Amazon search and propose scientifically grounded solutions. The main responsibilities include: Refining and revising the project plan to learn matcher embeddings for improving Amazon's product search engine; Creating datasets for training and evaluating machine learning models for this task; Evaluating the models, analyzing their performance, and reporting the findings to the wider team.

Mar. 2021 - May 2021

Applied Scientist Intern, Amazon, Berlin, Germany.

My role is to explore stochastic Transformers architecture and enhance it with uncertainty estimation with Monte Carlo method.

Mentor: Dr. Cheng Wang

Mar. 2020 - Jun. 2020

Applied Scientist Intern, Amazon Alexa AI, Aachen, Germany.

My role is to develop a lightweight adaptive Transformers model for natural language understanding in Alexa, which is able to remain more than 95% of the effectiveness while using less than 50% of the computational cost. Mentor: Dr. Daniil Sorokin

Teaching

Sep. 2018 – Oct. 2020 **Teachin**

Teaching Assistant, Bachelor's IR course, University of Amsterdam.

My role is to design the final search engine project, prepare pipeline code, grade, and answer students' questions.

Nov. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Teaching Assistant, Master's IR course, University of Amsterdam.

My role is to supervise two groups of students to wrap up their research projects, which includes weekly meetings, model implementation and paper writing.

Sep. 2018 - Dec. 2022

Thesis Supervisor, University of Amsterdam.

I have supervised 2 master students and 1 bachelor student for their thesis. My role is to help with weekly discussions, model design, result analysis and thesis writing.

Sep. 2018 - Now

Research Supervisor, University of Amsterdam and Shandong University. I have supervised 2 Ph.D. students and 2 master students for their research papers. My role is to help with weekly discussions, model design, result analysis and paper writing.

Activities

2021 - 2022

Campus intern ambassador, Amazon Campus Intern Ambassador Program 2021/22.

2020 - 2021

Reviewer and PC member, Journals (TOIS, IPM, TOIT, TOMM), conferences (ACL, SIGIR, AAAI, WWW, IJCAI, EMNLP, CIKM, WSDM, COLING, EACL).

2019 - 2020

Soos talk chair, IRLab, University of Amsterdam.

Sept. 2015 - Mar. 2016

Research grant application: Sentence similarity computation based on deep Learning. My role is the lead author in application for National Natural Science Foundation of China (No. 61672127).

May. 2014 - Sept. 2015

Research grant participation: English functional noun phrases identification. My role is research assistant, taking charge of model design and implementation in National Social Science Foundation of China (No.15BYY175).

Awards

- National scholarship for outstanding master students, top 1%.
 - Excellent graduate student in Dalian city, top 5%.
 - Outstanding master's thesis award, top 5%.

Talks

April. 2023	Generative AI towards scientific discovery, invited talk, Microsoft Research AI ₄ Science,
	Amsterdam, Netherlands. [slides].

- Oct. 2022 Learning embeddings to represent information retrieval systems, conference talk, Amazon Machine Learning Conference (AMLC), Berlin, Germany.
- July. 2022 Frontiers of collaborative task-oriented dialogue systems, invited talk, University College London (UCL), London, United Kingdom. [slides].
- Apr. 2022 Transformer uncertainty estimation with hierarchical stochastic attention, invited talk, Search Engine Amsterdam (SEA), Amsterdam, Netherlands. [link].
- Apr. 2021 A cooperative memory network for personalized task-oriented dialogue systems with incomplete user profiles, conference talk, WWW' 21, Ljubljana, Slovenia. [slides]. [vedio].
- Sept. 2020 Retrospective and prospective mixture-of-generators for task-oriented dialogue response generation, conference talk, ECAI' 20, Santiago de Compostela, Spain. [slides]. [video].
- Jun. 2020 Adaptive Transformers for efficient natural language understanding, invited talk, Amazon, Germany.
- Aug. 2019 SEntNet: Source-aware recurrent entity network for dialogue response selection, conference talk, IJCAI' 19 SCAI Workshop, Macao, China. [slides].
- Dec. 2016 Combining word embedding and semantic lexicon for Chinese word similarity computation, conference talk, NLPCC' 16, Kunming, China. [slides].
- Jun. 2016 DUT-NLP-CH @ NTCIR-12 temporalia temporal intent disambiguation subtask, conference talk, NTCIR' 16, Tokyo, Japan. [slides].

Publications

Conference Papers

- **Pei, Jiahuan**, Danushka Bollegala, and Omar Zaidan. "Learning Embeddings to Represent Information Retrieval Systems". In: *AMLC 2022 Deep Metric Learning and Semantic Similarity Search Workshop*. 2022.
- Pei, Jiahuan, Cheng Wang, and György Szarvas. "Transformer Uncertainty Estimation with Hierarchical Stochastic Attentions". In: *Proceedings of AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, AAAI 2022, CCF A*). 2022. OURL: https://arxiv.org/pdf/2112.13776.pdf.
- Yan, Guojun, **Jiahuan Pei**, Pengjie Ren, Zhaochun Ren, and Maarten de Rijke. "ReMeDi: Resources for Multi-domain, Multi-service, Medical Dialogues". In: International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR'22, **CCF A**). 2022.
- Pei, Jiahuan, Pengjie Ren, and Maarten de Rijke. "A Cooperative Memory Network for Personalized Task-oriented Dialogue Systems with Incomplete User Profiles". In: Proceedings of The Web Conference 2021 (WWW '21, CCF A). 2021. Our Unit https://arxiv.org/pdf/2102.08322.pdf.
- Pei, Jiahuan, Pengjie Ren, Christof Monz, and Maarten de Rijke. "Retrospective and Prospective Mixture-of-Generators for Task-oriented Dialogue Response Generation". In: Proceedings of the 24th European Conference on Artificial Intelligence (ECAI' 20, CCF B). Nov. 2019. URL: https://arxiv.org/pdf/1911.08151.pdf.

- Pei, Jiahuan, Pengjie Ren, and Maarten de Rijke. "A Modular Task-oriented Dialogue System Using a Neural Mixture-of-Experts". In: Proceedings of the 42nd International ACM SIGIR Workshop on Conversational Interaction Systems (SIGIR'19 WCIS Workshop). July 2019. URL: http://arxiv.org/abs/1907.05346.
- Pei, Jiahuan, Arent Stienstra, Julia Kiseleva, and Maarten de Rijke. "SEntNet: Source-aware Recurrent Entity Network for Dialogue Response Selection". In: Proceedings of the 28th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence Workshop on Search-Oriented Conversational AI (IJCAI' 19 SCAI Workshop). June 2019. URL: http://arxiv.org/abs/1906.06788.
- Ma, Jianjun, Mulangma Zhu, Degen Huang, and **Jiahuan Pei**. "Recognition of Syntactic Relationship between Clauses Using CRFs". In: *International Journal of Advanced Intelligence*. Vol. 10. Dec. 2018, pp. 1–14.
- Pei, Jiahuan, Cong Zhang, Degen Huang, and Jianjun Ma. "Combining Word Embedding and Semantic Lexicon for Chinese Word Similarity Computation". In: *Natural Language Understanding and Intelligent Applications (NLPCC'16, CCF C)*. Dec. 2016, pp. 766–777. URL: https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-50496-4_69.
- Pei, Jiahuan, Degen Huang, Jianjun Ma, Dingxin Song, and Leyuan Sang. "DUT-NLP-CH @ NTCIR-12 Temporalia Temporal Intent Disambiguation Subtask". In: Proceedings of the 12th NTCIR Conference on Evaluation of Information Access Technologies (NTCIR' 16). June 2016. URL: https://research.nii.ac.jp/ntcir/workshop/OnlineProceedings12/pdf/ntcir/TEMPORALIA/06-NTCIR12-TEMPORALIA-PeiJ.pdf.

Journal Articles

- Deng, Wentao, **Jiahuan Pei**, Zhaochun Ren, Zhumin Chen, and Pengjie Ren. "Intent-calibrated Self-training for Answer Selection in Open-domain Dialogues". In: *Transactions of the Association for Computational Linguistics (TACL)* (2023). **OURL:** https://arxiv.org/pdf/2307.06703.pdf.
- Ma, Jianjun, **Jiahuan Pei**, Degen Huang, and Dingxin Song. "Syntactic parsing of clause constituents for statistical machine translation". In: *International Journal of Computational Science and Engineering* (*IJCSE'18, JCR-Q3*) 17.1 (Sept. 2018), pp. 126–132. *Our URL*: https://doi.org/10.1504/IJCSE.2016.10004598.
- Huang, Degen, **Jiahuan Pei**, Cong Zhang, Kaiyu Huang, and Jianjun Ma. "Incorporating Prior Knowledge into Word Embedding for Chinese Word Similarity Measurement". In: *ACM Transactions on Asian and Low-Resource Language Information Processing (TALLIP' 18, SCI, JCR-Q2, IF=1.413)* 17.3 (Apr. 2018). **②** URL: https://doi.org/10.1145/3182622.
- Zhang, Cong, **Jiahuan Pei**, Kaiyu Huang, Degen Huang, and Zhangzhi Yin. "Semantic graph optimization algorithm based chinesemicroblog opinion summarization". In: *Journal Of Shandong University (Natural Science)* 52.7 (2017), pp. 59–65. URL: http://lxbwk.njournal.sdu.edu.cn/CN/10.6040/j.issn.1671-9352.1.2016.PC2.
- Ma, Jianjun, **Jiahuan Pei**, and Degen Huang. "Identification of English Functional Noun Phrases by CRFs and the Semantic Information". In: *Journal of Chinese Information Processing (CCF B, Chinese Journal)* 30 (Sept. 2016), pp. 59–66. URL: http://jcip.cipsc.org.cn/CN/Y2016/V30/I6/59.

Ongoing Work

Pei, Jiahuan, Fanghua Ye, Shuo Chen, Pengjie Ren, and Pablo Cesar. "AR-Dialog: Augmented Reality Guided Dialogue Agent for Industrial Assembly". ACL (Ongoing). 2024.

- Zhou, Xuemei, **Jiahuan Pei**, Irene Viola, and Pablo Cesar. "Distortion-guided Multitask Multimodal Learning for No Reference Point Cloud Quality Assessment". CVPR (Ongoing). 2024.
- Deng, Wentao, **Jiahuan Pei**, and Pengjie Ren. "Syllogistic Reasoning for Legal Judgment Analysis". EMNLP (Under Review). 2023.
- Liu, Yuanxing, **Jiahuan Pei**, Ming Li, Weinan Zhang, Wanxiang Che, and Maarten de Rijke. "Augmentation with Neighboring Information for Conversational Recommendation". (Ongoing). 2023.
- **Pei**, **Jiahuan**, Guojun Yan, Pengjie Ren, and Maarten de Rijke. "Mixture-of-languages Routing for Multilingual Dialogues". TOIS (Under Review). 2023.
- Zhang, Weijia, **Jiahuan Pei**, Mohammad Aliannejadi, and Evangelos Kanoulas. "Exploring the Validity of Faithfulness Metrics in Attribution Seeking for Large Language Models". CoNLL (Under Reivew). 2023.

References

- Prof. dr. Maarten de Rijke, Distinguished University Professor at University of Amsterdam.

 ☑ derijke@uva.nl
- Prof. dr. Danushka Bollegala, Professor at University of Liverpool, Amazon Scholar.

 ☑ danushka@liverpool.ac.uk
- **Prof. dr. Pengjie Ren,** Professor at Shandong University.
 - pengjie.ren@sdu.edu.cn